DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：KoU 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
おお…　神よ
Oh, my God...! M-Master Dan'ichiro...
だッ…　団一郎様
Rea...?
礼弥…
Rea!
礼弥ッ
Master Dan'ichiro!
団一郎様ッ
Thank goodness... you're still alive...
よかった…
生きていてくれたのだな
But you're covered in blood, aren't you?
だが…　血まみれではないか
Come, let's go to the hospital together.
さあ　一緒に病院へ行こう
Is something the matter?
どうか…　しましたか？
You have no pulse.
脈がないぞ
It's almost as though you...
これでは　まるで…
うふッ
Yes, I died. And then, I was reborn.
そう　私は死んだのです
そして　生まれ変わったのです
What do you mean? Wait! Don't go!
どういうことだ？
待って　行かないでくれ
My Rea!
私の礼弥ッ
No, I am no longer your daughter.
いいえ　私はもう
あなたの娘ではありません
That is because I am...
なぜなら　私は…
...no longer a person.
もう　人ではないのですから
How... did this happen...?
どうして…　こうなった？
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
Hey, did you hear?
ねえ　知ってます？
What?
なに？
The reason Miss Rea
has been going out at night lately
"A Normal... Girl..."
最近の礼弥様のお出かけ
男絡みらしいですよ
has to do with a boy.
That's old news. Want me
to tell you what the latest is?
遅い　もっと最新の情報
教えてあげようか？
Huh? What is it?
えッ　なんですか？
Miss Rea has run away from home.
礼弥様　家出したみたいよ
- Huh?
- You're kidding!
嘘ッ
それ　どういうこと？
What do you mean by that?
M-Madam Aria, welcome home.
亞里亞様…　お帰りなさいませ
Welcome home.
What do you mean, Rea has run away?
礼弥が家出したって
どういうこと？
Um, upon his return,
Master Dan'ichiro said that Rea has left.
お帰りになった団一郎様が
礼弥は去ってしまったと
おっしゃっていたので…
Where is he?
あの人は？
Well, he has been in the
bathroom since he came home.
お帰りになられてから
ずっと浴室に入られたままで…
The bathroom?
浴室？
Out of my way!
どきなさいッ
ああッ
And don't just cluster together there,
go tend to the yard!
あなた達も固まってないで
庭の手入れでもしてきなさいッ
She reeks of alcohol,
at this hour, already.
こんな時間から　お酒くさい
Lately, the host clubs have
been open in the afternoons, as well.
最近のホストクラブは
昼間もやってるからねえ
Host clubs?
ホストクラブ？
After all, since Master Dan'ichiro
won't pay attention to her,
団一郎様がお相手をなさらない
から　色々たまるんでしょ
she gets frustrated, you know?
Dear!
あなた！
礼弥が家出って
どういうことなの？
What's this I hear about Rea running away?!
She died... and then got back up...
死んだのに…
立ち上がったのだ
Huh?
She got up... and walked away from me.
立ち上がって…
私のもとを去っていったのだ
What are you talking about?
何言ってんの？　とにかく
子供に家出なんかされたら
Regardless, if our
child were to run away on us,
学園の理事長としての
私の立場が台なしよ！
my position as the school's
chairman would be ruined!
で　礼弥の居場所は分かってるの？
So, do you know where Rea is?
I would venture...
おそらく　降谷という
紫陽高校の男子生徒と
...that she is with the boy Furuya,
a student at Shiyo High School.
一緒におられます
Furuya? Who's that?
降谷？　誰よそいつ
Fu... ruya...
ふ…　るや…
Yes... He's the one...
そうだ　アイツが…
That boy has seduced Rea.
あの男が礼弥を
たぶらかしたのだ
That boy is the root of this evil!
あの男が諸悪の根源ッ
Furuya!!
降谷～！
Just you wait, Rea!
待っていろ礼弥
I will release you from him, and with my love,
お前をヤツから解放し
私の愛で　再び
身も心も清めてやるぞ！
I will purify you again, body and soul!
Sanka Private Girls' Academy
私立散華女子学園には
has a unique course called
"Meditative Needlework."
「瞑針」という特殊な科目がある
For ten minutes before their
first period, all of the students
それは全校生徒が
１時限目の前に１０分間
must continuously pass a
needle through a piece of cloth.
布きれに　ひたすら針を
通し続けるというもので
It's something that they do every morning,
裁縫を身につける
ということ以上に
providing the students
not only the skills for sewing,
一種の瞑想
精神鍛錬の行為として
but a kind of meditation,
and mental gymnastics, as well.
毎朝　必ず行われるのだそうだ
What's more, I've made a custom
of doing "Meditative Needlework"
しかも私は
就学前の幼少の頃から
every day without fail before school,
瞑針を習慣として
ever since I was a little girl.
毎朝　欠かさずやっていましたから
A-ha, that explains it.
はは～ん　なるほど
That's why you're able to
sew up your own wound like that.
それで　そんなふうに
自分の傷口が縫えるのか
No way!
て　ねーよ！
ちゃんと押さえててください
Oh, please, hold it closed!
I'm almost done.
あと少しですから
It's nice, not being able to feel pain.
痛みを感じないっていいですね
Listen, do you understand?! You died!
あのなあ　分かってるのか？
お前　死んだんだぞッ
Your skin is cold, you have no pulse,
and your pupils are dilated!
肌は冷たくなってるし
脈だってないし　瞳孔は開いてる
How can you laugh about this?!
なんで笑ってられるんだよ！
Well...
だって…
Well, for the first time...
だって　初めて
For the first time, I'm in a
boy's bedroom, so I'm... happy.
初めて…
男の子の部屋に入れたから
その…　嬉しくて
Huh?
はい？
Whew... All done, all done.
ふう～　終わった　終わった
Ranko!
蘭子先輩～
Would you like to stop and get
something sweet on the way home?
帰りに甘いものとか
食べてきませんか？
I found this pretty fancy open café.
なかなかオシャレなオープンカフェ
見つけたんですよ
Sorry, there's someplace
I need to go straight to today.
ごめん　今日は直行で
行きたいとこあるんだ
Oh, you don't say.
あらら　そうですか
Chihiro...
千紘のヤツ…
I don't care if you were chasing after Babu,
ばーぶちゃんを
追ってるからって
この私を狭い穴に
置き去りにするなんて　許さんッ
you're going to pay for
leaving me in that tight hole.
締めあげてやる～
I'm gonna wring your neck!
Huh? What are you ringing?
何をあげるんですか？
ううん　なんでもな～い
Mm-mm, nothing at all.
The evening air after
a heavy rain is nice, huh?
雨上がりの夕時っていいですね
She isn't thinking of
staying at my place tonight...
コイツ　もしかして今日
いや　この先
俺んちに居候するつもりじゃ…
or even, from now on, is she?
- Say, Furuya, do you see that?
ねえねえ降谷君　見える？
- Huh? I-I wasn't looking!
- Say, Furuya, do you see that?
ええッ！？　見てねえよ
You see? Up in that tree. It's Babu!
ほら　あそこの木の上
ばーぶちゃん
Look!
ほら
You're right!
ホントだ　たく心配させやがって
Geez, I was so worried about him.
お～い　ばーぶ
Hey, Babu!
His pupils are fixed...
黒目がハッキリしてる
ばーぶ
ばーぶちゃん
Sounds like Babu has a
stuffed-up nose. Is he okay?
なにか鼻が詰まってるみたい
大丈夫かな？
Oh, he's been like that since I first saw him.
ああ　あれは初めて会ったときから
I even took him to the vet,
but they said they couldn't fix it.
動物病院にも連れてったんだけど
治んなくてさ
He's always meowed like that.
It's why we call him "Babu."
ずっと　あんな鳴き声
だから「ばーぶ」
So that's why.
そうなんだ…
Geez, he's so laid back, unaware
of the grief he's put us through.
チェッ　こっちの苦労も知らないで
のんきにしやがって
ばーぶ
He says this tree is
the most comfortable one.
この木が一番心地がいいんだって
えッ？
Huh? You can understand
what Babu is saying?!
ばーぶが言ってること分かるの？
I think so, more or less.
なんとなく　そうなのかな～って
ね～ッ
Right?
Could it be that them both being zombies,
ひょっとして　ゾンビ同士で
なにかしら意思疎通ができるとか
they can communicate
with each other, or something?
For that matter,
despite becoming a zombie,
ゾンビになったからって
別に性格とか変わってないんだ
their personalities and
such haven't changed at all, huh?
うん？　なんですか
What is it?
Oh, nothing.
いやあ　別に…
Ah, I bet I know.
ああ～　ひょっとして
You wished I acted more like a zombie, don't you?
もっと私　ゾンビっぽいしぐさ
した方がいいんですかね？
Like so, the way you like, Furuya.
こう…　降谷君好みの
Honestly, she's hot enough just as she is.
正直　今でも十分
萌えるっつうの
Listen, are you sure
you're not anxious or anything
お前さ　ホントに
ゾンビになっちまったことに
about becoming a zombie?
不安とかねえんだな
ええ
Yes. After all, Furuya,
you're accepting responsibility for me.
だって降谷君が
責任取ってくれるんですもんね
So, how can I say this? When you
say I'm accepting responsibility,
その…　なんつうか
責任取るってのは
what exactly is it you want me to do?
具体的に俺にどうしてほしいって
ことなんだよ？
Usually, when you accept responsibility, it means...
普通　責任取るっつったら
Um, well, let's see...
う～んと　そうですね…
Go out together with me on shopping trips,
一緒に買い物に出かけたり
美術館とか行ったり…
and go with me to museums...
Huh?
はあ？
ゾンビ映画も見に行きましょうよ
Ah, and let's go see zombie movies, too!
Let's see, anything else...?
えっと　他には…
Oh, yeah, the amusement park!
そうそう遊園地！
- What is she saying? It's almost as though...
なに言ってんだ？
それって　まるっきりただの…
- And festivals during the summer, too!
- What is she saying? It's almost as though...
In other words, please let
me have all of the experiences...
つまり　私が今までできなかった
...that a normal girl should have,
but that I haven't had yet.
普通の女の子としての
すべての経験をさせてください
Uh, well... despite being a zombie,
えっと　ゾンビになったのに
普通の女の子としての経験って…
you want the experiences of a normal girl?
Huh? Is there something
wrong with that? Can't we do that?
何か　おかしいですか
ダメなんですか？
N-No, we can do those things...
いや　ダメとかじゃないけど…
Damn, is she strong.
すげー　バカ力
Furuya...
降谷君…
I'm...
私…　なん…　だか…
...somehow...
H-Hey, so suddenly...?!
おい　急にッ
Hey, you!
こら～！
Chihiro!
千紘～　出てこ～い！
Get out here!
やべッ　わんこ
Yikes! It's Wanko!
You finally show your face.
やっと出てきた　今朝は
よくも置き去りにしてくれたね
How dare you leave me behind this morning!
Hmm? Hey, do you have someone in your room?
ちょっと　今部屋に誰かいるの？
No! I'm all alone up here!
いねえよ　一人だよッ
Okay, I'm coming up there!
じゃあ部屋にあがるよ
Ah, wait, wait! I'll talk to you outside!
話し合いは外でするだあ
How come?
なんでよ？
Th-There are some male
reasons to consider, you know!
男の事情ってもんがあるんだよ
At this point, finding your dirty
magazines isn't going to shock me.
今さらエロ本とか
見つけたって　驚かないけど
Look, just wait there!
いいから　待ってろ
Okay, okay.
I'm going to head out for a bit.
Stay in the room, okay?
ちょっと俺　出かけるから
部屋から出るなよ
Got it?
いいなッ
はッ
話をするなら河原に行こう
Okay, if you want to talk,
let's go down to the riverbed!
Hold on, why the riverbed?
なんで河原よ！？
いいから　いいから
Never mind, just do it!
Come on, come on!
What was I about to do to Furuya...?
さっき　私…
降谷君に
なにしようとしたん…　だろ…
What is this feeling...?
この…　気持ちは…
ごめんな　置き去りにしたこと
すっかり忘れてた
I'm sorry! I completely forgot
that I left you back there!
You forgot?!
忘れてたあ！？
言い訳はそれだけ？
Is that your only excuse?
You're pissing me off!
ムカつくんだけどッ
痛い痛い
Ow! Ow! Ow! I'm sorry! I'm sorry, I say!
悪かった　悪かったってば
How is Babu?
ばーぶちゃんは？
大丈夫だったよ
He's fine. He didn't attack anyone, or anything.
別に人を襲ったりしてねえ
ふ～ん
ぐはッ
Good grief, carry a cell phone, will you?
まったく　アンタ携帯持ちなさいよ
ああいうとき
ホント困るんだから
It's really a pain at times like that.
I don't need a cell phone.
いらねえよ　携帯なんて
So what's going to happen to Babu now?
Will he be immortal forever?
でも　この先ばーぶちゃん
どうなるの？
ずっと不死身なわけ？
That's a good question.
そこだよなあ…
Oh, Furuya!
おッ　降谷！
ゲッ　なんだよ　今度はヤスタカ…
Ugh, now what? Yasutaka?
Furuya...!
ふ～る～や～！
Why, you...!
貴様～！
Please, introduce me to Rea!
俺にも礼弥たん
紹介してください！
Huh?
ああ？
降谷～　お前は神じゃ！
Furuya! You are a god!
- I mean, if you knew her, why didn't you say so?!
- Ow! Cut it out!
つうか知り合いだったら
なんで教えんかったんじゃ！
Ick.
キモ…
（モギ）ヤスタカ君　暴走しすぎだよ
Yasutaka is out of control.
Hey, by Rea, do you mean Sanka Rea?
ねえ　礼弥って
散華礼弥さんのこと？
Yes, yes, I mean Sanka Rea!
そうそう　その散華礼弥たん
Oh, you do know her, then?
なによ　知り合いだったんじゃない
And you deliberately asked
me "Do you know Sanka Rea?"
「散華礼弥って知ってる？」とか
わざとらしく聞いておいて
No, I wouldn't call her an acquaintance!
知り合いっつうか
たまたまちょっとな
We just happen to, you know...
You bastard!
たまたまで　なんて
大当たりとお近づきになった
How is it you just happened to, you know,
get close to a big deal like her?!
Still, that's good. He's not just
interested in zombie girls after all.
でもよかった　ゾンビっ娘にしか
興味がないわけじゃないんだ
いやいや　俺はガチで
ゾンビっ娘命だっつうの
Oh, no, zombie girls
are seriously my whole life!
And if nothing else, she's not a... huh?
第一　アイツはそんなんじゃ…
What is it?
どうしたの？
That's not true, is it?
そんなんじゃないのか…
She is now, in fact,
the zombie girl I've been longing for,
今のアイツは　まさに俺の
憧れ続けたゾンビっ娘で
and that zombie girl is up in my bedroom.
そのゾンビっ娘が
俺の部屋にいる？
Hey, now that I think about it,
what a dreamy situation!
おいおい　よく考えると
なんつー夢シチュエーション！
What are you smiling about?
なにニヤニヤしてんの？
してねえよお
I-I'm not.
Furuya is taking his time.
降谷君…　遅いなあ
I wonder who that girl is.
あの人…　誰なんだろう？
She was wearing a Sanka Girls' uniform.
散華女子の制服着てたけど
They sure seemed close, huh?
I'll bet she's Furuya's...
とても親しそうだったな～
やっぱり降谷君の…
At this point, finding your dirty
magazines isn't going to shock me.
今さらエロ本とか見つけたって
驚かないけど
そうだ
誰もいらっしゃらないみたいだし
Oh yeah. It doesn't sound
like anyone else is home, so...
It's okay for a zombie
to take a shower... isn't it?
ゾンビってシャワー浴びても
平気…　だよね？
I wonder why this feels so strange.
なんだろう　変な感じ
Oh, right. I can't
tell whether it's hot or cold.
あッ　そっか
熱いのか冷たいのか
分からないんだ
Still, it feels fresh.
でも　新鮮だなあ
こんなコンパクトなお風呂場って初めて
I've never been in a
bathroom so compact before.
なんだろこれ？
何に使うんだろう
I wonder what this is.
What do you use it for?
It's kind of firm and elastic. Could it be...
ちょっと硬くて　弾力がある…
ひょっとして　こういった感じで
エクササイズ…
you use it like this to do exercises?
U-Um...
あッ…　あのッ！
ええ～　人がいたの！？
Huh? There's someone home?!
きえッ！　貞ッ　貞なのかッ
Sada! Is that you, Sada?! Oh, Sada!
おお貞！　そうか
蘇りおったのかッ
Oh, so you've come back to life!
N-No, I'm...
いや　私は…
Sada, it was all my fault!
貞よ　わしが悪かった！
Um, you have the wrong person!
あのッ　人違いですッ
I'm home.
ただいま
貞～！
Sada!!
What's come over you, Gramps?
どうしたんだ　じーじ？
蘇りおったんじゃ
She's come back to life!
Sada has come back to me once again!
貞が再び　このわしのもとに
帰ってきてくれたんじゃ！
蘇ったかどうかは知らんが
I don't know if she's come back to life or not,
死んだばーばの名は
サダではなくキヨだが？
but my late granny's name was Kiyo, not Sada.
ええ　そうじゃったか？
Hmm? Is that right?
あれ？　わし今　なにしとんじゃ？
Huh? What was I just doing?
For Pete's sake...
まったく…
I think I got away with it.
ばれずにすんだかしら…
It's time to sit at the dinner table with Father.
お父様との食卓につく時間…
To think that I'd be in
someone else's home right now...
こんな時間に　他人の家で
しかも
男の人の部屋にいるなんて
and in a boy's bedroom, at that!
A lot sure has happened today.
今日は本当に色々あったなあ～
At last, I... am free.
やっと　私…
自由になれたんだ
And it's going to be like this... from now on...
これから先も…
ずっと　このまま…
Whew, I somehow managed to play it off.
なんとかごまかせた
But man, that Yasutaka was a pest.
しっかしヤスタカのヤツ
しつこかったなあ
He's got such incredible energy.
すげえエネルギーなんだから
他に使い道はないのかよ
Can't he channel it into something else?
おお　にーよ　今日は動物の内臓を
鍋で煮たものを食しますぞ
Oh, Brother, today we'll be
eating the innards of animals,
stewed in a pot.
Oh, sorry, I don't have much of an appetite.
ああ悪い　なんか食欲ないわ
萌路にも　ばれてないみたいだ
It looks like Mero hasn't found out, either.
Sorry I took so lon...
悪い　遅く…　うおッ
Yeah, welcobe hobe...
ああ～　お帰り～
おいおい　なんつう格好してんだよ
Hey, do you know what you look like?
ごめんなさい
シャワーお借りしらした…
I'b sorry... I used your shower...
つうか　まだぬれてんじゃねえか
カゼひくぞ
Yeah, and you're still wet, aren't you?
You'll catch cold.
Oh, that's okay.
I'b a zobbie, so I dot't catch cold.
ああ～　らいじょうぶれすよ
ゾンビらから　カゼひきませんよ～
Oh, right.
ああそっか
Huh? Hey, wait a second!
This conversation... it couldn't be...!
うん？　待てよ　おいおい
今の会話ってまさか…
これまで俺の脳内で描いていた
ゾンビっ娘との萌え会話だ！
Isn't this the kind of lovable conversation
with a zombie girl that I've
always played out in my mind?
ええ　じゃあ
おなかも壊したりしないんだ
W-Well then... you haven't
upset your stomach, or anything?
Huh? I'b a zobbie;
my stobach has already been upset.
う～ん？　ゾンビらから
すでにおなかは壊れてますよ～
だはッ！
It's too much, it's too much, it's too much!
たまらん　たまらん　たまらん！
Uh... Furuya...?
降谷君？
うおおお　すまねえ
Oh, sorry. My dreams are coming true,
and I kind of lost myself.
あまりの夢のかないっぷりに
我を忘れてしまった
つうか　お前も早く着替えろよ
Oh, and why don't
you hurry and get dressed?
Hmm... the thigg about that is...
う～ん
それがれすね～
実は…　らんらん
動けなくなってきて
as it happens, I'b gradually
becobing udable to mobe...
体が固まったみたいなんです…
By body... feels like it's getting stiff...
えッ？　固まったって
Huh? Getting stiff?
Is that why your speech is slurred?
ろれつが回ってないのは
そのせいなのか？
Yeah, probably...
あ～　そうれすねえ
なんだそれ？
まさか　薬が切れてるのか
What is this?
Could the drug be wearing off?
I need to touch you!
ちょっと
触るぞ
Could this be...?
もしかして　これって…
Rigor mortis...
死後硬直…
Rigor... bortis...?
しご…こうりょく？
Yeah, that's probably it. It's okay.
It's a natural phenomenon.
ああ　たぶんそうだ
大丈夫　自然な現象だよ
ふうん　さすが…　降谷…　君…
Leabe it to... Furuya...
...to udderstadd...
詳しいんだ…
Yeah...
Rea herself is still cheerful,
so she doesn't feel what's happening,
礼弥自身が明るいから
まったく実感がなかったけど
but while she may be conscious,
her body is in the exact same state
意識はあっても　彼女の体は
死んだ人間のそれと同じ状態…
that a dead person would be in.
それじゃ礼弥は
So then, Rea,
if we don't do something about this,
your flesh will start rotting,
このまま放っておくと
徐々に肉体が腐っていって
１ヵ月足らずで　白骨…
and within a month, you'll be a skeleton...
I have to do something.
なんとかしないと
普通の女の子としての
すべての経験をさせてください
Please let me have all of the experiences
that a normal girl should have.
I have to... preserve...
俺が　礼弥の体を…
...Rea's body...
維持らないと
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
なに？
もっと抑えてほしい
What? You want me to dial it back?
What do you mean by that?
Huh? I'm out of character?
どういう意味かな？
えッ　キャラクターが違う？
How can I be?
I'm doing it myself, aren't I?
違うもなにも
本人がやっているのではないか
Next time on Sankarea, episode 5:
"If You're a Zombie... That Means..."
"If She`s a Zombie... That Means..."
Everybody watch mero!
みんな見るめろ！
I've already sold myself on doing this;
こちらも納得して
やっておるのに
I can't have you throwing
cold water on everything now.
そんな水を差すようなことを
言われても困るわ